<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Nature of Things | the Nature of Things]]></title>
  <link href="http://schipperius.com/categories/nature-of-things/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://schipperius.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-25T09:01:01-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://schipperius.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Schipper]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Does A Programmer Really Do?]]></title>
    <link href="http://schipperius.com/articles/what-does-a-programmer-really-do"/>
    <updated>2012-09-16T19:45:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://schipperius.com/articles/what-does-a-programmer-really-do</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So how <em>do you</em> describe what a computer programmer really does?</p>

<p>Wikipedia describes <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_programming#Programmers">computer programming</a> as the process of designing, writing, testing, debugging, and maintaining the source code of a computer program, but this definition doesn't help me very much.<!-- more --></p>

<p>Ka Wai Cheung in his book, <a href="/resources">The Developer's Code: What Real Programmers Do</a>, describes software development as being similar to writing a novel or composing music.</p>

<p>Cheung goes on to say, that an author might write a chapter outline to get a general guide about what she wants to write about. But after that, she starts writing the real thing. Then she edits and repeats, a word change here or an entire chapter removed there.</p>

<p>And, a musician does not write sheet music for months and then hopes that the notes sound right. Instead, he plays and plays and finds a riff that works. He might have a few lines of lyrics and then finds the right chords around it, or vice versa. He builds the song in pieces and tests it in pieces.</p>

<p>The activities of a coder, novelist and musician are all very similar, each respective craft involves taking the audience (whether viewer, reader, or listener) from a starting point and engaging them through to an end point.</p>

<p>At its core, programming (at least in the context of building a website) is about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Storytelling">storytelling</a>; a means of conveying the events, words, images and sounds needed to share a particular experience whether it be of an entertainment, educational or commercial purpose.</p>

<p>This may, in part, explain why many of us appreciate a great <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ib-Qiyklq-Q">commercial</a> from <a href="http://www.coca-cola.com/en/index.html">Coca Cola</a>.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ib-Qiyklq-Q" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Or a great <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-CdopMJu7r4&amp;feature=related">guitar riff</a> from <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ps3717fqlkY&amp;feature=related">Keith Richards</a>.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/-CdopMJu7r4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Give In, Give Up, Give Over]]></title>
    <link href="http://schipperius.com/articles/give-in-give-up-give-over"/>
    <updated>2012-09-02T15:58:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://schipperius.com/articles/give-in-give-up-give-over</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the late sixties, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timothy_Leary">Timothy Leary</a> popularized the phrase "turn on, tune in, drop out" <em>apparently</em> given to him by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marshall_McLuhan">Marshall McLuhan</a>, known for coining famous expressions like "the medium is the message" and "the global village".</p>

<p>Well, I'm certainly no McLuhan, but I too have come up with a new phrase:<!-- more --></p>

<blockquote><p>Give In, Give Up, Give Over</p></blockquote>

<p>When you're weary, feeling small, when tears are in your eyes, when times get rough, and friends just can't be found, when you're down and out, when you're on the street, when evening falls so hard, when darkness comes, and pain is all around, give in, give up, and give over, you will feel better in the morning.</p>

<p>Obviously, this is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tongue-in-cheek">tongue-and-check</a>. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simon_%26_Garfunkel">Simon and Garfunkel's</a> fifth and final studio album <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bridge_Over_Troubled_Water">Bridge Over Troubled Water</a> and, in particular, the song by the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bridge_over_Troubled_Water_(song">same name</a> is a  brilliant work of art.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Take Nothing but Pictures]]></title>
    <link href="http://schipperius.com/articles/take-nothing-but-pictures"/>
    <updated>2012-07-22T07:32:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://schipperius.com/articles/take-nothing-but-pictures</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have visited more than 20 of the 58 <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_national_parks_of_the_United_States">national parks</a> found in the US.</p>

<p>Throughout these parks are many walking and hiking trails and at the start of these trails would be a sign that read:<!-- more --></p>

<blockquote><h2><small><small><img src="/images/articles/take-nothing-but-pictures.jpg/" title="Take nothing but pictures, leave nothing but footprints." alt="Take nothing but pictures, leave nothing but footprints" /> "Take nothing but pictures, leave nothing but footprints."</small></small></h2>

<p><span><small>Photograph Credit: <a href="http://www.jcolivera.com/">JC Olivera</a>. Used with permission.</small></span></p></blockquote>

<p>Now, I am far from being a naturalist, I am certainly no <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Muir">John Muir</a> but this phrase has stuck with me and has influenced my thinking.</p>

<p>It's great to see a sign that can influence your behaviour without hitting you over the head with it.</p>

<p>The idea that you can leave something in the same condition as you first experienced it, conveys a deep feeling of respect without shoving it up your face.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>