<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Web Development | the Nature of Things]]></title>
  <link href="http://schipperius.com//categories/web-development/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://schipperius.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-04T21:24:29-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://schipperius.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Schipper]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Customizing Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://schipperius.com/articles/customizing-octopress"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T17:12:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://schipperius.com/articles/customizing-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What follows is an incomplete list of the customizations I have made to my Octopress site, and the resources I used to learn the steps.<!-- more --></p>

<ol>
<li><p>One thing missing “out of the box” is a linked category or tag list in the sidebar. Dan Watson <a href="http://www.dotnetguy.co.uk/post/2012/06/25/octopress-category-list-plugin/">explains</a> just how to do this, and it works. Yeah!</p></li>
<li><p>Rake new_post does not work with zsh.
This error can be resolved with the following <a href="http://ryanarneson.com/blog/2012/04/07/rake-new-post-doesnt-work-with-zsh/">work around</a></p></li>
<li><p>Building a <a href="http://www.donothackcore.com/blog/2012/05/06/contact-form-in-octopress">Contact Form - Part One</a>
using <a href="https://github.com/arshad/Google-Form-Octopress">Google Docs</a>, and adding notifications to the <a href="http://www.donothackcore.com/blog/2012/05/07/contact-form-in-octopress-making-notifications-awesomer/">Contact Form - Part Two</a></p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beginning with Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://schipperius.com/articles/beginning-with-octopress"/>
    <updated>2012-08-05T18:24:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://schipperius.com/articles/beginning-with-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few months ago, I was looking for a blogging tool and stumbled upon <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> which as of late, has been receiving considerable attention.<!-- more --></p>

<p>The <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/">documentation</a> reads great for developers, but for non-IT guys like me, it does not feel complete.</p>

<p>If you are new to this stuff, you may want to add a few proficiencies to the <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/setup/">setup page</a> including: HTML, CSS, SASS, Ruby, Jekyll, Liquid and Markdown.</p>

<p>Once you create your new blog, study the contents of the root folder, and learn how the pieces all fit together.</p>

<p>In reading a lot of new Octopress blogs, a large number of developers have commented on how they were able to set up their site in a matter of hours, this reminds me of the hype around creating a blog with Ruby on Rails in 15 minutes.</p>

<p>People learning these tools, technologies and methodologies for the first time will spend a day for every hour a seasoned professional will spend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
